Jascha Heifetz Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1911-1974 (Box 1-247)
  - Music by Other Composers (Box-folder 15/2-11, Box 16-247)
    - Composers
      - Wieniawski, Henryk
        - [Scherzo tarantelle, op. 16], Piano-violin score and part (Box-folder 202/3)
        - [Scherzo tarantelle, op. 16; arr.], Orchestral score (Box-folder 202/4)
        - [Scherzo tarantelle, op. 16; arr.], Parts (Box-folder 202/5)
        - [Souvenir de Moscou, op. 6], Piano-violin score and part; Various editions (2) (Box-folder 202/6)
      - Wolf, Hugo
        - Eichendorff Lieder, Piano-vocal score; 2 vols. (Box-folder 202/7)
        - Goethe Lieder, Piano-vocal score; 4 vols. (Box-folder 203/1)
        - [Italienisches Liederbuch], Piano-vocal score; 3 vols. (Box-folder 203/2)
        - [Italiensche Serenade, string quartet, G major], Miniature score (Box 217)
        - [Italiensche Serenade, string quartet, G major], Parts (Box-folder 203/3)
        - Lieder nach verschiedenen Dichtern, Piano-vocal score; 2 vols. (Box-folder 203/4)
        - Mörike Lieder, Piano-vocal score; 4 vols. (Box-folder 203/5)
        - Spanisches Liederbuch, Piano-vocal score; 4 vols. (Box-folder 204/1)
      - Ysaye, Eugène
        - Caprice d'après l'étude en forme de valse de C. Saint Saëns, Piano-violin score and part (Box-folder 204/2)
        - [Sonatas, violin, op. 26], Violin score (Box-folder 204/3)
      - Zikoff, Franz
        - [Corespondenzkarten potpourri, op. 99], Piano score (Box-folder 204/4)
      - Zimbalist, Efrem
        - Concert phantasy on Rimsky-Korsakow's "le coq d'or", Piano-violin score and part (Box-folder 204/5)
        - [Quartet, strings, E minor], Score (Box-folder 204/6)
        - [Quartet, strings, E minor], Parts (Box-folder 204/6)
        - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 1], Holograph piano-violin score (Box-folder 204/7)
      - Zsolt, Nàndor
        - [Quintet, strings, piano], Piano score and parts (Box-folder 204/8)
        - Satyr and Dryads, Piano-violin score and part (Box-folder 204/9)
      - Unidentified
        - [Giga, violin, piano], Piano-violin score and part (Box-folder 205/1)
        - [Instrumental ensemble work], 5 leaves of handwritten score (Box-folder 205/2)
        - Lamps in the street, Typed lyric sheet w/ ammendations (Box-folder 205/3)
        - [Sonata, piano], Printed piano score, incomplete; Note: fragment of last movement (Box-folder 205/4)
    - Collections
      - Album de musica popular mexicana no. 2, Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 205/5)
      - Alte Meister des Violinspiels, Piano-violin score and part; Edited by Arnold Schering (Box-folder 205/6)
      - Bergerettes/Romances and songs of the eighteenth century, Piano-vocal score; Edited by J.B. Wekerlin (Box-folder 205/7)
      - A century of russian song, Piano-vocal score; Edited by Kurt Schindler (Box-folder 205/8)
      - Folk-dance music, Piano score; Edited by Elizabeth Burchenal and C. Ward Crampton (Box-folder 205/9)
      - Kerr's collection of reels and strathspeys, Violin score (Box-folder 206/1)
      - Kerr's modern dance album for the violin, Violin score (Box-folder 206/2)
      - Lieder-Sammelbuch für die jüdische Schule und Famile, Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 206/3)
      - 100 Magyar nóta, Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 206/4)
      - The modern violin soloist, Piano-violin score and part; Edited by George Perlman (Box-folder 206/5)
      - Ouvertüren Album, Piano (4 hands) score; 2 vols.; Edited by Richard Kleinmichel (Box-folder 207/1)
      - Ouvertüren Album, Piano (4 hands) score (Box-folder 207/2)
      - 51 piano pieces from the modern repertoire, Piano score (Box-folder 207/3)
      - Songs to Jehovah's praise, Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 207/4)
  - Music Lists and Catalogs (Box 208, Box-folder 207/5-9)
    - Chamber music repertory and piano trios. Typewritten list. (Box-folder 207/5)
    - Jascha Heifetz: arrangements/transcriptions/encores, Catalogs published by Carl Fischer. Various editions (2) (Box-folder 207/6)
    - Jascha Heifetz music library (files), Folders: 207/7 Typewritten list of music originally in Heifetz's two black file cabinets; compiled by Claire Hodgkins 207/7 Laid in: letter 207/8 Orchestral parts and scores 207/8 Typewritten list with annotations by Heifetz 207/9 [Various lists] 207/9 Typewritten lists of Chamber music, concerti, viola music, small pieces, violin and piano pieces with annotations by Heifetz (Box-folder 207/7-9)
    - Index card file of Heifetz's library, Contents: Cream cards: music (violin) in cabinets Pink: records by Heifetz Blue: records (other than Heifetz) Cream: music (other than violin) Other: books (Box 208)
- Programs, 1917-1974 (Box 219-233, Box 240)
  The Programs series contains concert programs of his performances from 1911 to 1974.
  The Programs series are arranged alphabetically by performance location (city or country).
  - 1917-21, 241 (Box 218)
  - 1922-26, 188 (Box 219)
  - 1927-29, 153 (Box 220)
  - 1930-32, 164 (Box 221)
  - 1933-35, 174 (Box 222)
  - 1936-38, 126 (Box 223)
  - 1938-41, 158 (Box 224)
  - 1941-45, 127 (Box 225)
  - 1946, 1947, 1949, 132 (Box 226)
  - 1949-53, 129 (Box 227)
  - 1953-56, 1958-59, 1961-63, 150 (Box 228)
  - 1964-68, 1970, 1972, 1974 (Box 229)
  - Radio programs: 1933-49, 90 (Box 229)
  - Radio programs: 1950-58 (Box 230)
  - Program files, 372 (Box 230)
  - Program files; program notebook, 133 (Box 231)
  - Oversize programs 1917-33 (Box 232)
  - Oversize programs 1933-72 (Box 233)
  - Scrapbook of Programs 1911-17? (Box 240)
- Correspondence, 1864-1986 (Box-folder 5/7, Box-folder 55/4, Box-folder 123/13, Box-folder 134/5, Box-folder 232/1-2, Box 234)
  The Correspondence series contains letters from such important musical figures of the twentieth-century as Leopold Auer, Benjamin Britten, Sergei Prokofiev, George Bernard Shaw, and Sir William Walton.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Auer, Leopold, 1918-26, 5 (Box 234)
  - Boulanger, Nadia, n.d., 1 (Box 234)
  - Britten, Benjamin, 1950, 1 (Box 234)
  - Burgin, Richard, n.d., 1 (Box-folder 55/4)
  - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1930, 1 (Box 234)
  - Chaliapin, Feodor, 1930, 1 (Box 234)
  - Conus, Julius, 1926, 1 (Box 234)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1924, 1 (Box 234)
  - David, Ferdinand, 1864, 1; Note: not to Heifetz (Box 234)
  - Dinicu, Grigoras, 1930, 1 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Edelmann, Chester M., 1976, 1 (Box 234)
  - Elgar, Sir Edward, 1920, 2 (Box 234)
  - Garden, Mary, 1924, 1 (Box 234)
  - Gaubert, Phillipe, 1926, 1 (Box 234)
  - Glazunov, Alexander, 1928, 1 (Box 234)
  - Gliere, Reinhold, 1945, 1 (Box 234)
  - Grossman, Mrs. Herbert, 1979, 1 (Box 234)
  - Juon, Pavel, 1931, 1 (Box 234)
  - Kenny International Corp., 1975-76, 3 (Box 234)
  - Leclerc de Hautecloque, 1947, 1 (Box 234)
  - Medtner, Nicolas, 1951, 1 (Box 234)
  - Melba, Nellie, 1920, n.d., 3 (Box 234)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, n.d., 1 (Box 234)
  - Moeran, Ernest John, 1946 Dec. 31, 1; Note: not to Heifetz (Box-folder 123/13)
  - Nero, Paul, 1952, 1 (Box-folder 134/5)
  - Pierné, Gabriel, 1928, 1 (Box 234)
  - Prokofiev, Sergei, 1938, 1 (Box 234)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1986, 1 (Box 234)
  - Ries, Ferdinand, 1922, 1 (Box 234)
  - Sarasate, Pablo, n.d., 1 (Box 234)
  - Scott, Cyril, 1937, 1 (Box 234)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1920, 1 (Box 234)
  - Shostakovich, Dmitri, 1934, 1 (Box-folder 232/1)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1975-78, n.d., 12 (Box 234)
  - Toscanini, Arturo, n.d., 1 (Box 234)
  - Walton, William, 1939, 1 (Box-folder 232/2)
  - Wilson, Pete, 1986, 1 (Box 234)
- Photographs, 1901-1991 (Box 235-239, Box 241)
  The Photographs series contains photographs of Heifetz as well as other prints.
  The Photographs series are organized by size, rather than date order, as many of them contain unusually large date spans that frequently overlap.
  - Heifetz
    - Portraits alone (Box-folder 235/1-3)
    - Portraits with violin (Box-folder 235/4-6)
  - Heifetz family
    - Florence Heifetz (Box-folder 236/1)
    - Florence, Josepha and Robert Heifetz (Box-folder 236/2-3)
    - Frances and Jay Heifetz (Box-folder 236/4)
  - Heifetz with others
    - Identified (Box-folder 236/5-7)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 236/1-2)
  - Others
    - Identified (Box-folder 237/3)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 237/4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Objects (Box-folder 237/5)
    - Electricar (Box-folder 237/6)
    - Heifetz et al. on farm (Box-folder 237/7)
    - Heifetz's hands (Box-folder 237/8)
    - RCA Italiano, May 1964 (Box-folder 237/9)
    - Recording session (Box-folder 237/10)
    - "They shall have music" (Box-folder 237/11-12, Box-folder 238/1-4)
    - Violins of Heifetz (Box-folder 238/5)
    - Negatives (Box 239)
    - Oversize photos (Box 241)
- Scrapbooks, 1911-1974 (Box 248-256, Box 259, Box 260-262, Box 264-271, Box 273-274, Box 280)
  The Scrapbooks series contains 34 scrapbooks.
  The Scrapbooks series are organized by size, rather than date order, as many of them contain unusually large date spans that frequently overlap.
  - "Heifetz Tour 1926-28", Clippings 1913-57 (Box 248)
  - "JoJo & Bobby", Photographs n.d. (Box 249)
  - "Season 1923-24", Clippings 1923-36 (Box 249)
  - "Scrapbook", Clippings 1911-26 (Box 249)
  - [no title] family album, blue-grey cover, Photographs 1911-n.d. (Box 250)
  - [no title] black notebook, German, Yiddish, Russian clippings 1911-17 (Box 250)
  - [no title] cloth bound album, Photographs 1909-n.d. (Box 250)
  - "Budapest Koncert IV/Yáci-ucca 23/Jascha Heifetz", Clippings 1938 (Box 250)
  - "Anniversary Publicity Auer Concert (Carnegie Hall)", Clippings n.d. (Box 250)
  - "Recuerdo, Chile", Clippings 1934 (Box 250)
  - "Souvenirs JH", Correspondence, souvenirs 1912-34? (Box 251)
  - "Scrapbook" inside cover: "Press Clippings 1939-1942-1944 etc.-", Clippings 1939-46 (Box 252)
  - "Jascha Heifetz Summer Concert", Photographs 1949 (Box 253)
  - "Heifetz miscellaneous/1924-25 & 1927-28", Clippings, memorabilia (Box 253)
  - [no title], Photos 1926-27 (Box 254)
  - "News cuttings", Clippings (international) 1923-34 (Box 254)
  - "Clippings 1946-50", Clippings 1946-Sept. 1952 (Box 255)
  - Pressbooks, Contents: Heifetz pressbook Pressbook cardboard impressions Pressbook for for cine "opera" Mexico RCA pressbook Teatro Colon press Pressbook 1942-43 Various circulars and programs Heifetz-Piatigorsky concerts publicity Sitka summer music festival (Box 256)
  - "Souvenir Book (1947?) (No Patches)", Photos, clippings, memorabilia 1914-52 (Box 259)
  - [no title], Clippings Jan. 1940-July 1940 (Box 260)
  - "Jascha Heifetz Personal", Clippings 1937-41 (Box 261)
  - [no title], Clippings June 1938-July 1939 (Box 262)
  - "1928-29-1930/Los Angeles, New York-Continent/also 1934-32/USA/England & France/World Tour-1931-32/Continent and Foreign", Clippings (Box 264)
  - "Souvenirs etc. 1953", Clippings, memorabilia 1910-71 (Box 265)
  - "Japan tour Apr-May 1954 & Europe etc. 1954, 1955, 1956, 1957", Photographs 1954-60 (Box 266)
  - "Clippings 1952", Clippings 1952-81 (Box 267)
  - [no title], Clippings, photographs 1939-40 (Box 268)
  - "Nov. 15, 1935-Mar 30th 1936", Clippings (Box 269)
  - "Souvenirs H 1938-1939", Passports, correspondence, memorabilia, programs, photos 1916-40? (Box 270)
  - "Front", Photos, memorabilia, 1937-49 (Box 271)
  - [no title] red velvet album, Postcards (Russian), 1 photograph laid in (Box 273)
  - [no title] black photo album, Photographs, n.d. (Box 274)
  - "The side show", Inside cover: "Dec. 9, 1959 New York"; Contents: Correspondence, memorabilia 1921-40 U.N. 11th anniversary, memorabilia, photographs (Box 274)
  - [no title] brown cover illustrated with picture of a fox chasing a duck, Postcards, 1909-15, n.d. (many blank) removed and rehoused BOXES 280B and 280C; Inside cover inscribed by Olevskii (Box 280A, Box 280B, Box 280C)
- Miscellaneous, 1901-1991 (Box 257-258, Box 272, Box 275-279)
  The Miscellaneous series consists of Artwork, Honorariums, Posters and other miscellaneous items.
  Arranged by format.
  - Artwork
    - Heifetz portrait by Norman David (Box 275)
    - Heifetz portrait by Mortensen (Box 275)
    - Heifetz portrait with camera by Mortensen, 1933 (Box 275)
    - Heifetz charcoal sketch by Eugen Spiro (Box 275)
    - Heifetz portrait with poem "The world genius" by Haruko Fujahara (Box 275)
    - Heifetz caricature [signature unknown] (Box 275)
    - Hand impressions (2), 1933 (Box 275)
    - "Symphoniphobias" a set of 16 prints by Glen Morley, 1950 (Box 275)
    - 1976 Calendar of 13 pen and ink drawings by Jennie Livingston (Box 275)
    - Heifetz caricature by Eudora Silver, 1940 (Box 275)
    - Cartoon in pen and ink by Xavier Cugat (Box 275)
  - Honorariums
    - Northwestern University, Degree of Doctor of Music, 1949; Program for convocation (Box 272)
    - Jewish Artists Fraternity Inc., Honorary Membership, 1935 (Box 272)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Articles by Heifetz (Box 257)
    - Boston Symphony 85th anniversary dinner and Golden Trumpet Ball program, 1965 (Box 257)
    - Copyright registrations (Box 257)
    - Miscellaneous repertory lists (Box 257)
    - Correspondence and clippings re. instituting 911 service (Box 257)
    - Advertisement for Martin Marietta (Box 257)
  - Posters
    - Posters 1911, 1938, n.d., Rolls BOXES: 276-279 (Box 258, Box 276-279)
Appendix I: Books Retained and Shelved with the Jascha Heifetz Collection
Applebaum, Samuel and Sada Applebaum
The way they play
Neptune City, New Jersey: Paganiniana Publications, 1972
Table of contents annotated
With the artists
New York: John Market & Co., 1955
Inscribed by the authors
Auer, Leopold
Graded course of violin playing, vol. 1
New York: Carl Fischer, 1926
Moîa Shkola Igry Na Skripke [My method for violin playing]
Leningrad: Triton, 1933
Inscribed by the author
My long life in music
New York: Frederick A. Stokes, 1923
Inscribed by the author
Violin master works and their interpretation
New York: Carl Fischer, 1925
Inscribed by the author
Baruzzi, Arnaldo
La Casa Nuziale: The home of Antonio Stradivari, 1667-1680
Translated by Desmond Hill
London: William E. Hill & Sons, 1962
Inscribed by Benno and Sylvia Rabinof
Broekman, David
The shoestring symphony
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1948
Inscribed by the author
Brook, Donald
Violinists of to-day
London: Rockliff, 1948
Inscribed by Albert Sammons
Calvocoressi, M.D. and Gerald Abraham
Masters of Russian music
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1936
Chevalley, Heinrich, ed.
Arthur Nikisch: Leben und Wirken
Berlin: Bote & Bock, 1922
Inscribed by Bennie Koodlach
Cramer, Edward E.
The Basis of artistry in violin playing
Dallas, Texas: Southwest Printing, 1936
Inscribed by the author
Dandelot, Arthur
Petits mémoires musicaux
Paris: Éditions de "La Nouvelle Revue," [1936]
2 copies
inscribed by the author
Fortina, Carl
The accordion, as written
North Hollywood, California: Holly-Pix Publishing Company, 1961
Inscribed by the author
Gately, Francis Cabrini
Musical mileage
Paterson, New Jersey: St. Anthony Guild Press, 1940
Inscribed by the author
Heine, Heinrich
Nuits Florentines
Translated by André Coeury
Paris: J. Schiffrin et Cie., 1923
Watercolor painting by illustrator on frontispiece
Hill, W. Henry; Arthur F. Hill, and Alfred E. Hill
Antonio Stradivari: his life and work (1644-1737)
London: William Hill and Sons, 1902
reprint, New York: Dover Publications, 1963
Inscribed by Michael Caracappa
Hodgson, Percival
Motion study and violin playing
London: The Strad, 1934
Inscribed by the author
Hoffmann, E.T.A.
Salvator Rosa Translated by Albert Béguin
Paris: J. Schiffrin, 1926
Watercolor painting by illustrator on frontispiece
Homburg, R.
Legal rights of performing artists
Translated by Maurice Speiser
New York: Baker, Voorhis & Company, 1934
Inscribed by the translator
Hurok, Sol and Ruth Goode
Impresario: a memoir by S. Hurok
New York: Random House, 1946
Inscribed--name illegible
Kahn, Roger
How the weather was
New York: Harper and Row, 1973
Inscribed by "The Shrinking Violet"--probably the author
Kunik, A.
O Russko-Vizantiiskikh Monetakh. [On Russian-Byzantine currency].
St. Petersburg: [s.n.], 1860
Annotated
Leclerc, Charles Victor
La 2 E DB, Général Leclerc, combattants et combats en France
Paris: Arts et Métiers Graphiques, 1945
Inscribed by the author
Marek, George R.
Puccini
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1951
Inscribed to Heifetz from the author
McKinney, Laurence
People of note
New York: E.P. Dutton and Company, 1940
Inscribed by Elisabeth Prentiss
Molloy, Maurice S. and Marie A. Snyder
My musical rating
New York: National Digest Co., 1927
Quiz book--some answers written in book
Mozart, Leopold
Versuch einer gründlichen Violinschule, entworfen und mit 4 Kupfertalfeln sammt einer Tabelle versehen von Leopold Mozart In Verlag des Verfassers
Augspurg: Gedruckt bey J. J. Lotter, 1756
Gründliche Violinschule, mit vier Kupferyafel und einer Tabelle Dritte vermehrte Auflage
Augsburg: Gedruckt und zu finden bey J. J. Lotter und Sohn, 1787
O'Connell, Charles
The Victor book of the symphony
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1935
Inscribed by the author
Petrov, A.
Instrumentovka
St. Petersburg: [s.n.], 1913
Annotated
Pincherle, Marc
Vivaldi
Translated by Christopher Hatch
New York: W. W. Norton, 1962
Inscribed by Michael Caracappa
Prévost, Abbé
Manon Lescaut
Paris: J. Schriffin, 1929
Watercolor painting by illustrator on frontispiece
Radio Corporation of America
The 50-year history of RCA Victor Records
New York: RCA Department of Information, 1953
Letter to Heifetz in book
The recordings of Heifetz: RCA Victor Red Seal
[New York?]: RCA, n.d.
Ran, Leyzer, ed.
Jerusalem of Lithuania
Egg Harbor City, New Jersey: The Laureate Press
Reis, Claire
Composers in America
New York: Macmillan, 1938
Inscribed by the author
Rothschild, Germaine de
Luigi Boccherini
Paris: Libraire Plon, 1962
Saleski, Gdal
Famous musicians of Jewish origin
New York: Bloch Publishing Company, 1949
Inscribed by the author
Schauffler, Robert Haven
Fiddler's folly
New York: Henry Holt, 1942
Inscription
Smith, Moses
Koussevitzky
New York: Allen, Towne & Heath, Inc., 1947
Inscribed by the author
Spaeth, Sigmund
The common sense of music
New York: Boni and Liveright, 1924
Inscribed by the author
Spalding, Walter R
Music: an art and a language 7th ed
Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt Co., 1920
Inscribed by the author
Steinway, Theodore
People and pianos
New York: Steinway and Sons, 1953
Inscribed by the author
Venth, Carl
My musical memories
San Antonio, Texas: Alamo, 1939
Inscribed by Cathinka Venth--Carl's wife
Volpe, Marie
Arnold Volpe: bridge between two musical worlds
Coral Gables, Florida: University of Miami Press, 1950
Inscribed by the author
Wagner, Richard
The ring of the Niblung: a trilogy with a prelude by Richard Wagner
Translated by Margaret Armour
New York: Garden City Publishing Co, Inc., 1939
Inscribed by Raul Garcia
Wartanoff, Boris
Le vie amoureuse de Paganini
Geneva: Celta, n.d.
Inscribed by the author
Watson, James
Stamps and music
London: Faber and Faber, 1962
Annotated
Musical America 68(February 1948)
Musical America 72(February 1952)
Texas almanac and state industrial guide
Dallas, Texas: A. H. Belo Corporation, 1947
Inscribed by Amelia and Gorge McDaniel
Wisdom 1(June 1956)
Appendix II: Books Transferred to General Music Division Collections
Armando, Walter G.
Paganini: Eine Biographie
Hamburg: Rütten & Loening, 1960
Beethoven, Ludwig van
The letters of Ludwig van Beethoven, 2 vols.
Edited by A.C. Kalischer
Translated by J.S. Shedlock
New York: E.P. Dutton, 1909
Beyschlag, Adolf
Die Ornamentik der Musik
Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1908
Bowen, Catherine Drinker and Barbara Von Meck
Beloved friend: the story of Tchaikovsky and Nadejda Von Meck
Garden City: Garden City Publishing, 1941
Brockway, Wallace and Herbert Weinstock
Men of music: their lives, times, and achievements
New York: Simon and Schuster, 1939
Buchner, Alexander
Musical instruments through the ages
Translated by Iris Urwin
London: Spring Books, n.d
Chaudoir, [Stanislaw], Baron de
Aperçu sur les monnaies russes et sur les ronnaies étrangères qui ont eu cours en Russie, 3 vols.
St Petersburg: Chez F. Bellizard et co, 1836
Clain-Stefanelli, Elvira Eliza
Select numismatic bibliography
New York: Stack's, 1965
Dannreuther, Edward
Musical ornamentation, 2 vols.
London: Novello and Company, n.d.
Decca Records, Inc.
A complete catalog of all 78 RPM, 45 RPM, and long play 33 1/3 rpm records
New York: Decca Records, Inc., 1953
A complete catalog of 45 rpm Decca records
[New York?]: Decca Records, Inc., 1951
A complete catalog of long play Decca records
[New York?]: Decca Records, Inc., 1951
A complete listing of Decca Gold Label Series records
[New York?]: Decca Records, Inc., n.d.
Popular record catalog
New York: Decca Records, Inc., 1949
Popular single records catalog
New York: Decca Records, Inc. 1955
Record review
[New York?]: Decca Records, Inc., n.d.
Supplement 1c to volume I
[New York?]: Decca Records, Inc., [1953]
Dent, E.J
Mozart's operas: a critical study
London: Chatto & Windus, 1913
Dutch Treat Club
Eighty-first anniversary for members and their guests on the occasion of the annual dinner
[New York]: [s.n.], [1987]
Edwards, Sutherland, H.
The life of Rossini
London: Hurst and Blackett, 1869
Ershov, P.
Konëk-Gorbunok [A tale in verse]
Moscow: Akademia Press, 1934
Farish, Margaret K.
String music in print
New York: R.R Bowker Company, 1965
Fay, Amy
Music study in Germany
London: Macmillan and Co., 1887
Flagstad, Kirsten
The Flagstad manuscript
Compiled by Louis Biancolli
New York: Van Rees Press, 1952
Flesch, Carl
Memoirs
London: Rockliff, 1957
Memoirs
New York: Macmillan, 1958
Gaisberg, Fred W.
Music on record
London: Robert Hale Limited, 1958
Gallet, Luciano
Estudos de Folclore
Rio de Janeiro: Carlos Wehrs & Cia., 1934
Gavoty, Bernard
Les grands interprètes
Geneva: Éditions René Kister, n.d.
Gil', Khr., and A. Il'in
Russkiia monety, S 1801-1904 [Russian currency: 1801-1904]
St. Petersburg: A. Il'in Cartographic Institution Publishers, 1904
Girdlestone, C. M.
Mozart and his piano concertos
Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1952
Hadden, J. Cuthbert
The operas of Wagner
London: T.C. & E.C. Jack, Ltd, [1908]
Hamilton, Clarence G.
Outlines of music history
Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1924
Horejs, Antonín
Antonín Dvorák: the composers life and work in pictures
Prague: Artia, 1955
Ken, A. G.
Beethoven: his life and works
St. Petersburg: V. Val'ter, 1909
Kolb, Annette
Mozart
Chicago: Henry Regnery Company, 1956
Laloy, Louis
La musique chinoise
Paris: Libraire Renouard, n.d.
Laurie, David
Reminiscences of a fiddle dealer
Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1925
Lochner, Louis P.
Fritz Kreisler
[S.l.]: Macmillan, 1950
Malm, William P.
Japanese music and musical instruments
Rutland, Vermont: Charles E. Tuttle Company, 1959
Manos, Constantine
Portrait of a symphony
New York: Basic Books, 1960
Masson, Kelvin
The written labors of 14 master violinists
Urbana, Illinois: American String Teachers Association, 1970
[Moscheles, Charlotte]
Life of Moscheles, 2. vols
Translated and adapted by A.D. Coleridge
London: Hurst and Blackett, 1873
Newman, Ernest
More stories of famous operas
New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1943
Paganelli, Sergio
Musical instruments from the Renaissance to the 19th century
Translated by Anthony Rhodes
London: Hamlyn, 1970
Poidras, Henri
Critical and documentary dictionary of violin makers, old and modern
Translated by Arnold Sewall
Rouen: Imprimerie de la Vicomté, 1928
Prout, Ebenezer
The Orchestra, 2 vols.
London: Augener, 1898, 1899
Respighi, Elsa
Ottorino Respighi
Translated by Gwyn Morris
London: Ricordi, 1962
Rimsky-Korssakow, Nicolai
Grundlagen der orchestration, 2 vols.
Edited by Maximilian Steinberg
Translated by Alexander Elukhen
Berlin: Russicher Musikverlag, 1922
Rolland, Romain
Beethoven the creator
Translated by Ernest Newman
New York: Harper & Brothers, 1934
Musicians of today, 4th ed.
Translated by Mary Blaiklock